

Mohammed Ibrahim Mohammed Altom

Full Stack Developer Phone: +249129039378

Address: Almatar, Africa Street

Languages: Arabic {Native} & English {Fluent}

Email: yantos@outlook.com

Profile:

Experienced Full Stack Developer, proficient at both front end and back end technologies, has an excellent practical knowledge about the guidance and principles to follow when going through the Software Development life Cycle, which makes me efficient in both the quality and the development duration of the product.

Experience:

Freelancer {Software developer}

Nov, 2019-To date

Engaging clients and assessing their needs then provide solutions based on gathered requirements.

Volunteer Translator [English ⇔ Arabic] at Coursera

Dec, 2019-To date

Translating the courses of coursera platform from English to Arabic to make it available to those Who cannot Understand English.

Software engineer &Database Administrator at Sudanese Postal Services Co. ltd Aug, 2018- Aug, 2019

I was responsible of maintaining the point of sale system the company uses, developing its components, administrating the database as well as developing new sub systems & software that help the company.

Projects:

Developing Web Admin Broker for algoji enterprize

International Postal system (IPS) / sudapost pos Integration project

Mgal accounting System / sudapost pos Integration project

Sudapost vehicles system

Updating sudapost Real estate Investment system

Education:

BSC in Information Technology / University of Khartoum

Oct, 2011 - Oct, 2017

Courses:

Full stack web developing (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT and PHP)

Institution: Youth Foundation for Information Technology

Developing with Asp.net Core

Java essential training

PHP for web designers

CSS animation

JAVASCRIPT and AJAX

Foundations of Web Security

■ Technical Skills:

Full stack web developing

ASP.net Core MVC c#

Asp.net Web Forums

Logging and third party Logging libraries {Log4net}

PHP / AJAX / JQUERY

Fetching/calling Web API

Validation Using JQUERY Obtrusive

Sockets &listeners

OOP / Web Scrapping

Async functions

JAVA, Python (ArcGis), c++ and visual basic (basic skills)

Artificial Intelligence (basic Knowledge)

Photoshop & Multimedia softwares (audio & video)

Microsoft Office Suite & macros

Personal Skills:

Fast learner.

Critical thinking & Decision Making.

Attention to details.

Excellent analytical skills.

Creativity.

Ability to Work under pressure in group or as an Individual.